

Demetrice Williams

Professional Summary

Detail-oriented software engineer with 2 years of software development experience with the ability to carry projects from design to implementation to integration.

A highly motivated individual with a strong passion for front-end engineering who fully embraces teamwork but is very capable of working independently.

Work History

FORVIS - Associate Software Engineer

07/2021 - Current

- Designed and presented mockups/wireframes for stakeholder approval.
- Performed as a Lead Software Engineer on two internal projects.
- Built RESTful APIs that served data to both Blazor framework and JavaScript libraries
- Designed and implemented UI features for new and existing projects.
- Implemented system design concepts such as caching.
- Participated in code reviews with both the engineering and product team to gain constructive feedback
- Created a design guide to serve as the company standard.
- Ensured proper documentation and reports in all stages of the product life cycle.

United States Air Force - Human Resources Assistant

10/2020 - 03/2021

- Provided office automation support for in/out processing of military personnel using multiple office automation software with varied functions.
- Organized soldier orientation schedules for all incoming soldiers.
- Briefed incoming soldiers on daily tasks.
- Prepared monthly, weekly, and daily logs using Microsoft Office Suite.

United States Army - Sergeant

12/2016 - 10/2020

- Supervised soldiers and provided technical guidance to ensure the accomplishment of all missions.
- Responsible for the ordering, receiving, issuing and accountability of individual, organizational, installation and expendable supplies and equipment.
- Utilized Microsoft Excel worksheets and PowerPoint presentations to develop, publish, and present unit training requirements and training schedules.
- Planned, coordinated, and training events including multiple companies.
- Created, organized, and taught classes relating to communications for internal unit training.

✓ demetrice_williams@hotmail.com

(907) 342-9233

Links

- Portfolio
- LinkedIn
- GitHub

Skills

- Python (Django)
- C# (ASP.NET Core)
- Blazor Server / WebAssembly
- JavaScript (React)
- HTML / CSS
- SQL (SSMS)
- Git (GitLab / GitHub)
- UI/UX Design
- Agile Development
- REST APIs

Education

10/01/2021

American Military University
Bachelor of Arts – BA, Management

06/07/2021

DevCodeCamp

Milwaukee, WI

Full-Stack Software Development

 Coursework in C#, ASP.NET Core, Python (Django), JavaScript (React.js), SQL (MySQL), Git, and REST API